

# SÉBASTIEN MISCHLER

Self-taught developer with 20 years of experience in digital fabrication, project management and team building, open-source contributor interested in problem solving and making the DX/UX a top priority, seeking to integrate a team of passionated developers.

contact@skarab42.dev +41 78 789 32 50 Geneva - CH github.com/skarab42 twitch.tv/skarab42

### **SKILLS**

Javascript (Expert)
Typescript (Intermediate)
TypeScript Internal API (Intermediate)
AST concept & data structure (Beginner)
JS Linting tooling (Intermediate)
GitHub Actions (Beginner)
Rollup (Proficient)
Svelte (Proficient)

## **LANGUAGES**

French (Native language)
English (Functional/Technical)

## **EDUCATION**

Electrician (CFC) CFPT, Geneva 1997 - 2002

## **AWARDS**

Winner of the Twitch Channel Points API Hackathon for the Top 10 Channel Points Integrations (2021-04-16)

<u>devpost.com/software/valheim-twitch-mod</u>

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### JAVASCRIPT & TYPESCRIPT DEVELOPER

Open source development & full-time streamer | Geneva | 2020 - 2021

- Created a <u>Visual Studio Code extension</u> to improve experience of TypeScript developers writing documentation by automatically generating Markdown from their code and the associated AST generated using the TypeScript Compiler API.
- Developed a complete <u>streaming software</u> for Twitch creators to quickly & easily automate every aspect of their streams, from automated alerts, thanking donors and new subscribers to creating custom animations that appear seamlessly on screen.
- Live streamed every part of each projects, from the conception stage to the development and deployment, on Twitch, as a coworking experience that became one of the most watched french streams in the Software and Game Development category.

#### **CO-FOUNDER & FABMANGER**

Fablab Onl'Fait | Geneva | 2016 - 2020

- Created the first Fab Lab (Fabrication Laboratory) in Geneva open to everyone
  wanting to prototype and make their own digital fabrication.
- Assisted dozens of people through each step of their projects from the brainstorming to their original creation.
- Contributed to the expansion of the laboratory by creating new positions, collaborating with local partners, individuals, associations, communities and authorities.

#### **COOPERATOR**

Itopie informatique | Geneva | 2014 - 2016

- Developed 3D parts for the rehabilitation process of obsolete computer equipment such as SSD to HDD drive holders.
- Handled customer service for a workshop including hardware repair with a team of ten people.

#### **TEAM LEADER & TRAINER**

Rhône Electra SA | Geneva | 2007 - 2014

- Supervised teams of electricians involved in the maintenance of various installations at the ICRC and UNHCR.
- Trained and supervised apprentices who joined the company.

#### CO-FOUNDER & DESIGNER & PHP DEVELOPER

c0m création | Geneva | 2005 - 2007

- Created the company to help local companies develop their online presence.
- Assisted clients from the conception phase, through the design process to the actual development and deployment of their new online services.

#### **ELECTRICIAN**

Rhône Electra SA | Geneva | 2002 - 2005

 Installed and maintained electrical equipment in a wide-range of settings like network installation and home automation.